ONYEBUEKE IFEANYI SAMUEL

onyebuekes93@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/onyebueke -ifeanyi-1b52411b4/ www.github.com/Samuel202093 https://samuel-onyebueke.netlify .app +2348131880839

EXPERIENCE

Loc Tech I.T Institute, Port-Harcourt — *Web development Bootcamp*

April 2021 - December 2022

I participated in an intensive coding bootcamp, honing my programming skills and collaborating with other students to develop innovative projects.

Community Secondary School Ojiegbe, Ebony — Teacher

August 2019 - August 2020

I.C.T Instructor

EDUCATION

Federal Polytechnic Oko, Anambra — *HND*

November 2016 - November 2018

Computer Engineering

Federal Polytechnic Oko, Anambra — *ND*

October 2013 - August 2015

Computer Engineering

Immanuel Comprehensive High School, Port-Harcourt —

WAEC

September 2005 - August 2011

WAEC

ABOUT

Gender: Male

Marital Status: Single,

Nationality: Nigeria

State: Anambra

L.G.A: Orumba-south

Language: English

PROFILE

Analytical-minded and creative team player with a strong background in Computer Engineering who is keen in applying academic foundation and technical experience.

Accustomed to providing integral technical support.

Experience in Microsoft Word, Website Design and Development and also have the ability to function independently and in fast-paced team environments.

PROJECTS

E-commerce Web Application

Github link: https://github.com/Samuel202093/e-commerce-frontend https://github.com/Samuel202093/e-commerce-server-side

Technologies:Html5, Css, Javascript, ReactJs, Redux, react-router-dom, react-icons, Framer-motion, ChartJs, NodeJs, Express, JWT, Nodemailer, MongoDb, Stripe.

Description: I developed the frontend of the application using html5, css, javascript, reactjs, chartjs, redux, react-router-dom. The react-router-dom was used to handle routing in the application, redux which is an external state management library was used to manage states within the application and chartjs was used for data visualization by the admin.

Furthermore, I built the backend of the application using Nodejs, Express, JWT, Nodemailer, Stripe, MongoDb, Stripe. I built a CRUD Restful Api for admin using express, JWT was used for user authentication, Nodemailer was used for email verification, Stripe was my payment gateway and Mongodb was used as my database to save users and products data.

Data Entry Application(Backend)

Github link: https://github.com/Samuel202093/exam server

Technologies: NodeJs, Express, JWT, Postgresql, Cloudinary, Knex

Description: I built the application using the aforementioned technologies. In the application certain tasks can only be carried out by the admin in which this was achieved by authentication and authorization using JWT. I handled file uploads using cloudinary to optimize the server and also I integrated knex which is an sql query-builder with postgresql to save data to the database.

Food Recipe Application

Link: https://food-recipe-port.netlify.app/

Github link: https://github.com/Samuel202093/food_recipe

Technologies: Html5, TailwindCss, Javascript, ReactJs, UseContext,

react-router-dom, react-icons

Description: I built the application using reactjs. TailwindCss was used for styling of the application, react-router-dom was used for routing, react-icons for integrating icons and useContext was used for handling state in the application.

SKILLS

Proficient in Html, Css,
Tailwind Css, Javascript,
ReactJs, Redux, Bootstrap,
Typescript, NodeJs, MongoDb,
Next Js and React Native in
view, Postgresql, computer
literacy, efficient time
management, excellent
communication, adept to new
technologies, team-player,
excellent problem-solving,
creative ability and logical
approach to work.

REFEREES

Mr. Igbe Cletus

Software Engineer C.E.O Netcle Technologies Port-Harcourt. Tel: 07060722008

Mr. Duff Ini. D. Caleb

Software Instructor Rivers I.C.T Center(Techcreek) Port-Harcourt.

Tel: 08068800748